[
    {
        "question": "When did Nigeria gain independence from Britain?",
        "options": [
            "1963",
            "1957",
            "1958",
            "1960"
        ],
        "answer": "1960"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was Nigeria’s first Prime Minister?",
        "options": [
            "Nnamdi Azikiwe",
            "Obafemi Awolowo",
            "Ahmadu Bello",
            "Tafawa Balewa"
        ],
        "answer": "Tafawa Balewa"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was the first President of Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Yakubu Gowon",
            "Nnamdi Azikiwe",
            "Ernest Shonekan",
            "Olusegun Obasanjo"
        ],
        "answer": "Nnamdi Azikiwe"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital city of Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Abuja",
            "Enugu",
            "Lagos",
            "Kano"
        ],
        "answer": "Abuja"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which year did Nigeria become a republic?",
        "options": [
            "1960",
            "1999",
            "1963",
            "1979"
        ],
        "answer": "1963"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who moved the motion for Nigeria’s independence in 1953?",
        "options": [
            "Nnamdi Azikiwe",
            "Obafemi Awolowo",
            "Herbert Macaulay",
            "Anthony Enahoro"
        ],
        "answer": "Anthony Enahoro"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which organization was founded by Herbert Macaulay in 1923?",
        "options": [
            "AG",
            "NPC",
            "NNDP",
            "NCNC"
        ],
        "answer": "NNDP"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which paper was founded by Nnamdi Azikiwe in 1937?",
        "options": [
            "West African Pilot",
            "Daily Times",
            "Nigerian Tribune",
            "The Guardian"
        ],
        "answer": "West African Pilot"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which party dominated the Northern Region in the 1950s?",
        "options": [
            "NNDP",
            "NPC",
            "AG",
            "NCNC"
        ],
        "answer": "NPC"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which party was led by Obafemi Awolowo in the 1950s?",
        "options": [
            "AG",
            "NCNC",
            "NPC",
            "NNDP"
        ],
        "answer": "AG"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which British official amalgamated Northern and Southern Nigeria in 1914?",
        "options": [
            "Lord Lugard",
            "Hugh Clifford",
            "John Macpherson",
            "Arthur Richards"
        ],
        "answer": "Lord Lugard"
    },
    {
        "question": "When was Abuja officially made Nigeria’s capital?",
        "options": [
            "1991",
            "1993",
            "1999",
            "1987"
        ],
        "answer": "1991"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the national currency introduced in 1973?",
        "options": [
            "Cedi",
            "Pound",
            "Naira",
            "Kobo"
        ],
        "answer": "Naira"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who designed the Nigerian flag in 1959?",
        "options": [
            "M.T. Mbu",
            "Wole Soyinka",
            "Michael Taiwo Akinkunmi",
            "Benedict Odiase"
        ],
        "answer": "Michael Taiwo Akinkunmi"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which anthem replaced 'Nigeria, We Hail Thee' in 1978?",
        "options": [
            "Land of Hope",
            "Lift Every Voice",
            "Arise, O Compatriots",
            "Great Nigeria"
        ],
        "answer": "Arise, O Compatriots"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which year did the Nigerian Civil War end?",
        "options": [
            "1968",
            "1971",
            "1970",
            "1969"
        ],
        "answer": "1970"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which city was Nigeria’s capital before Abuja?",
        "options": [
            "Ibadan",
            "Kano",
            "Lagos",
            "Kaduna"
        ],
        "answer": "Lagos"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which Nigerian region introduced free primary education in 1955?",
        "options": [
            "Western Region",
            "Eastern Region",
            "Northern Region",
            "Mid-Western Region"
        ],
        "answer": "Western Region"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what year was the Mid-Western Region created?",
        "options": [
            "1951",
            "1957",
            "1963",
            "1960"
        ],
        "answer": "1963"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which oil field first produced crude oil in commercial quantity in 1956?",
        "options": [
            "Bonny",
            "Brass",
            "Oloibiri",
            "Warri"
        ],
        "answer": "Oloibiri"
    },
    {
        "question": "Nigeria became a member of OPEC in which year?",
        "options": [
            "1971",
            "1967",
            "1973",
            "1979"
        ],
        "answer": "1971"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of Nigeria’s national oil company founded in 1977?",
        "options": [
            "NOC",
            "NNDC",
            "NNPC",
            "NPC"
        ],
        "answer": "NNPC"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who led Biafra during the Civil War?",
        "options": [
            "Philip Effiong",
            "Yakubu Gowon",
            "Benjamin Adekunle",
            "Chukwuemeka Odumegwu Ojukwu"
        ],
        "answer": "Chukwuemeka Odumegwu Ojukwu"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was Head of State during most of the Civil War?",
        "options": [
            "Yakubu Gowon",
            "Aguiyi-Ironsi",
            "Murtala Mohammed",
            "Shehu Shagari"
        ],
        "answer": "Yakubu Gowon"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which date is celebrated as Democracy Day since 2019?",
        "options": [
            "May 27",
            "June 12",
            "October 1",
            "May 29"
        ],
        "answer": "June 12"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which event is associated with 1993 in Nigerian politics?",
        "options": [
            "Amalgamation of Nigeria",
            "Annulment of the June 12 election",
            "Adoption of the 1999 Constitution",
            "Civil War outbreak"
        ],
        "answer": "Annulment of the June 12 election"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which university was Nigeria’s first, founded in 1948?",
        "options": [
            "University College Ibadan",
            "UNN",
            "ABU Zaria",
            "UNILAG"
        ],
        "answer": "University College Ibadan"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who founded the Action Group in 1951?",
        "options": [
            "Nnamdi Azikiwe",
            "Tafawa Balewa",
            "Aminu Kano",
            "Obafemi Awolowo"
        ],
        "answer": "Obafemi Awolowo"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which protectorates were amalgamated in 1914?",
        "options": [
            "Niger and Borno",
            "Northern and Southern Nigeria",
            "Lagos and Eastern Nigeria",
            "Benin and Oyo"
        ],
        "answer": "Northern and Southern Nigeria"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which empire had its capital at Oyo-Ile?",
        "options": [
            "Sokoto Caliphate",
            "Kanem-Bornu",
            "Oyo Empire",
            "Benin Kingdom"
        ],
        "answer": "Oyo Empire"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which kingdom is famous for brass and bronze artworks?",
        "options": [
            "Ife Kingdom",
            "Benin Kingdom",
            "Oyo Empire",
            "Nupe Kingdom"
        ],
        "answer": "Benin Kingdom"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who founded the Sokoto Caliphate in 1804?",
        "options": [
            "Usman dan Fodio",
            "Afonja",
            "Muhammad Bello",
            "Ahmadu Bello"
        ],
        "answer": "Usman dan Fodio"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Nok culture is best known for which art form?",
        "options": [
            "Glass beads",
            "Wood carvings",
            "Stone pyramids",
            "Terracotta sculptures"
        ],
        "answer": "Terracotta sculptures"
    },
    {
        "question": "Queen Amina was associated with which city-state?",
        "options": [
            "Zazzau (Zaria)",
            "Katsina",
            "Kano",
            "Ilorin"
        ],
        "answer": "Zazzau (Zaria)"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many states does Nigeria have today?",
        "options": [
            "32",
            "38",
            "30",
            "36"
        ],
        "answer": "36"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many geopolitical zones are in Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "6",
            "7",
            "5",
            "4"
        ],
        "answer": "6"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which year were 12 states first created from the regions?",
        "options": [
            "1976",
            "1967",
            "1963",
            "1987"
        ],
        "answer": "1967"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is celebrated on October 1st in Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Democracy Day",
            "Children’s Day",
            "Independence Day",
            "Workers’ Day"
        ],
        "answer": "Independence Day"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was Nigeria’s first Executive President (1979)?",
        "options": [
            "Shehu Shagari",
            "Olusegun Obasanjo",
            "Umaru Yar’Adua",
            "Nnamdi Azikiwe"
        ],
        "answer": "Shehu Shagari"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who became civilian President on May 29, 1999?",
        "options": [
            "Ibrahim Babangida",
            "Ernest Shonekan",
            "Goodluck Jonathan",
            "Olusegun Obasanjo"
        ],
        "answer": "Olusegun Obasanjo"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was assassinated in a coup attempt in 1976?",
        "options": [
            "Aguiyi-Ironsi",
            "Sani Abacha",
            "Yakubu Gowon",
            "Murtala Mohammed"
        ],
        "answer": "Murtala Mohammed"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which conference partitioned Africa among European powers in 1884–85?",
        "options": [
            "Paris Summit",
            "London Convention",
            "Berlin Conference",
            "Vienna Congress"
        ],
        "answer": "Berlin Conference"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which city hosted the 1977 FESTAC?",
        "options": [
            "Ibadan",
            "Lagos",
            "Kaduna",
            "Abuja"
        ],
        "answer": "Lagos"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which nationalist is known as the 'father of Nigerian nationalism'?",
        "options": [
            "Herbert Macaulay",
            "Michael Okpara",
            "Aminu Kano",
            "Ahmadu Bello"
        ],
        "answer": "Herbert Macaulay"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which group led the 1929 protests against taxation in Eastern Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Kano farmers",
            "Egba men",
            "Zaria traders",
            "Aba women"
        ],
        "answer": "Aba women"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which movement formed in 1934 challenged colonial rule?",
        "options": [
            "Nigeria People's Party",
            "Unity Party",
            "National Reform League",
            "Nigerian Youth Movement"
        ],
        "answer": "Nigerian Youth Movement"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which city is famous for the Osun-Osogbo Sacred Grove?",
        "options": [
            "Ogbomoso",
            "Osogbo",
            "Ilesa",
            "Abeokuta"
        ],
        "answer": "Osogbo"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which cultural landscape in Adamawa is a UNESCO site (1999)?",
        "options": [
            "Erin-Ijesha",
            "Gashaka-Gumti",
            "Ikom Monoliths",
            "Sukur"
        ],
        "answer": "Sukur"
    },
    {
        "question": "What was Nigeria’s official language after independence?",
        "options": [
            "Hausa",
            "English",
            "Yoruba",
            "Igbo"
        ],
        "answer": "English"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which river forms part of Nigeria’s name?",
        "options": [
            "Cross",
            "Gongola",
            "Benue",
            "Niger"
        ],
        "answer": "Niger"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which constitution introduced elective principles in Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Lyttleton Constitution (1954)",
            "Macpherson Constitution (1951)",
            "Clifford Constitution (1922)",
            "Richards Constitution (1946)"
        ],
        "answer": "Clifford Constitution (1922)"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which constitution widened regional autonomy in 1954?",
        "options": [
            "Lyttleton Constitution (1954)",
            "Macpherson Constitution (1951)",
            "Richards Constitution (1946)",
            "Clifford Constitution (1922)"
        ],
        "answer": "Lyttleton Constitution (1954)"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which constitution replaced the Richards Constitution?",
        "options": [
            "Lyttleton Constitution (1954)",
            "Macpherson Constitution (1951)",
            "Independence Constitution (1960)",
            "Clifford Constitution (1922)"
        ],
        "answer": "Macpherson Constitution (1951)"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which constitution came with independence?",
        "options": [
            "Republican Constitution (1963)",
            "1979 Constitution",
            "Independence Constitution (1960)",
            "1999 Constitution"
        ],
        "answer": "Independence Constitution (1960)"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which constitution made Nigeria a republic?",
        "options": [
            "Independence Constitution (1960)",
            "1979 Constitution",
            "Republican Constitution (1963)",
            "1999 Constitution"
        ],
        "answer": "Republican Constitution (1963)"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was the first military Head of State of Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Ibrahim Babangida",
            "Murtala Mohammed",
            "Johnson Aguiyi-Ironsi",
            "Yakubu Gowon"
        ],
        "answer": "Johnson Aguiyi-Ironsi"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who led Nigeria after the 1966 counter-coup?",
        "options": [
            "Yakubu Gowon",
            "Murtala Mohammed",
            "Olusegun Obasanjo",
            "Aguiyi-Ironsi"
        ],
        "answer": "Yakubu Gowon"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who succeeded Murtala Mohammed in 1976?",
        "options": [
            "Olusegun Obasanjo",
            "Yakubu Gowon",
            "Ibrahim Babangida",
            "Shehu Shagari"
        ],
        "answer": "Olusegun Obasanjo"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which military ruler annulled the June 12, 1993 election?",
        "options": [
            "Ibrahim Babangida",
            "Olusegun Obasanjo",
            "Yakubu Gowon",
            "Sani Abacha"
        ],
        "answer": "Ibrahim Babangida"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who became Head of State after the Interim Government in 1993?",
        "options": [
            "Abdulsalami Abubakar",
            "Sani Abacha",
            "Ernest Shonekan",
            "Umaru Yar’Adua"
        ],
        "answer": "Sani Abacha"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who handed power to civilians in 1999?",
        "options": [
            "Abdulsalami Abubakar",
            "Ibrahim Babangida",
            "Olusegun Obasanjo",
            "Sani Abacha"
        ],
        "answer": "Abdulsalami Abubakar"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many states were created in 1967?",
        "options": [
            "19",
            "12",
            "21",
            "30"
        ],
        "answer": "12"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many states were created in 1976?",
        "options": [
            "12",
            "30",
            "21",
            "19"
        ],
        "answer": "19"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many states were created in 1987?",
        "options": [
            "24",
            "30",
            "21",
            "19"
        ],
        "answer": "21"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many states were created in 1991?",
        "options": [
            "32",
            "21",
            "30",
            "36"
        ],
        "answer": "30"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many states were created in 1996?",
        "options": [
            "34",
            "36",
            "30",
            "32"
        ],
        "answer": "36"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which city hosted Nigeria’s independence celebrations in 1960?",
        "options": [
            "Enugu",
            "Ibadan",
            "Kaduna",
            "Lagos"
        ],
        "answer": "Lagos"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the green color on the Nigerian flag said to represent?",
        "options": [
            "Unity",
            "Peace",
            "Agriculture",
            "Justice"
        ],
        "answer": "Agriculture"
    },
    {
        "question": "What does the white color on the Nigerian flag represent?",
        "options": [
            "Agriculture",
            "Freedom",
            "Peace",
            "Unity"
        ],
        "answer": "Peace"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which river joins the Niger at Lokoja?",
        "options": [
            "Cross",
            "Gongola",
            "Benue",
            "Kaduna"
        ],
        "answer": "Benue"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which region was led by Ahmadu Bello in the 1950s?",
        "options": [
            "Mid-Western Region",
            "Northern Region",
            "Western Region",
            "Eastern Region"
        ],
        "answer": "Northern Region"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which year did Ibadan become Nigeria’s capital?",
        "options": [
            "1993",
            "1999",
            "1990",
            "1991"
        ],
        "answer": "1991"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which year did Ilorin become Nigeria’s capital?",
        "options": [
            "1993",
            "1990",
            "1999",
            "1991"
        ],
        "answer": "1991"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which year did Kano become Nigeria’s capital?",
        "options": [
            "1990",
            "1993",
            "1991",
            "1999"
        ],
        "answer": "1991"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which year did Zaria become Nigeria’s capital?",
        "options": [
            "1993",
            "1999",
            "1990",
            "1991"
        ],
        "answer": "1991"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which empire is historically linked with the city of Abuja?",
        "options": [
            "Kanem-Bornu",
            "Benin Kingdom",
            "Oyo Empire",
            "Sokoto Caliphate"
        ],
        "answer": "Benin Kingdom"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which empire is historically linked with the city of Ibadan?",
        "options": [
            "Sokoto Caliphate",
            "Benin Kingdom",
            "Kanem-Bornu",
            "Oyo Empire"
        ],
        "answer": "Benin Kingdom"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which empire is historically linked with the city of Zaria?",
        "options": [
            "Sokoto Caliphate",
            "Oyo Empire",
            "Benin Kingdom",
            "Kanem-Bornu"
        ],
        "answer": "Benin Kingdom"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which empire is historically linked with the city of Kano?",
        "options": [
            "Oyo Empire",
            "Sokoto Caliphate",
            "Kanem-Bornu",
            "Benin Kingdom"
        ],
        "answer": "Benin Kingdom"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which year did Benin City become Nigeria’s capital?",
        "options": [
            "1999",
            "1990",
            "1991",
            "1993"
        ],
        "answer": "1991"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which year did Abuja become Nigeria’s capital?",
        "options": [
            "1990",
            "1993",
            "1999",
            "1991"
        ],
        "answer": "1991"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which empire is historically linked with the city of Benin City?",
        "options": [
            "Sokoto Caliphate",
            "Oyo Empire",
            "Benin Kingdom",
            "Kanem-Bornu"
        ],
        "answer": "Benin Kingdom"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which empire is historically linked with the city of Ilorin?",
        "options": [
            "Kanem-Bornu",
            "Benin Kingdom",
            "Oyo Empire",
            "Sokoto Caliphate"
        ],
        "answer": "Benin Kingdom"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which charter empowered the Royal Niger Company in the late 19th century?",
        "options": [
            "1890 ordinance",
            "1914 charter",
            "1900 charter",
            "1886 charter"
        ],
        "answer": "1886 charter"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was the High Commissioner that proclaimed the Protectorate of Northern Nigeria in 1900?",
        "options": [
            "Walter Egerton",
            "Frederick Lugard",
            "Hugh Clifford",
            "Donald Cameron"
        ],
        "answer": "Frederick Lugard"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which constitution introduced regional Houses of Assembly more broadly?",
        "options": [
            "Macpherson Constitution (1951)",
            "Clifford Constitution (1922)",
            "Richards Constitution (1946)",
            "Lyttleton Constitution (1954)"
        ],
        "answer": "Macpherson Constitution (1951)"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which revolt took place in Abeokuta in 1918 against taxation and colonial policies?",
        "options": [
            "Aba Women's War",
            "Adubi War",
            "Satiru Uprising",
            "Ekumeku War"
        ],
        "answer": "Adubi War"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which Niger Delta king led a resistance culminating in the 1895 attack on Akassa?",
        "options": [
            "King Koko of Nembe",
            "Jaja of Opobo",
            "Dappa Pepple",
            "Nana Olomu"
        ],
        "answer": "King Koko of Nembe"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was exiled after the 1897 British punitive expedition to Benin?",
        "options": [
            "Oba Eweka II",
            "Oba Esigie",
            "Oba Ovonramwen",
            "Akenzua II"
        ],
        "answer": "Oba Ovonramwen"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which anti-colonial movement fought in Anioma/Western Igbo areas between 1898–1914?",
        "options": [
            "Mau Mau",
            "Satiru Movement",
            "Egba United govt",
            "Ekumeku Movement"
        ],
        "answer": "Ekumeku Movement"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which 1906 uprising in Sokoto Province opposed colonial rule?",
        "options": [
            "Satiru Uprising",
            "Taraba Revolt",
            "Kiriji War",
            "Adubi War"
        ],
        "answer": "Satiru Uprising"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which agreement in 1967 sought to avert war between Nigeria and the Eastern Region?",
        "options": [
            "Lagos Accord",
            "Aburi Accord",
            "Kano Accord",
            "Enugu Pact"
        ],
        "answer": "Aburi Accord"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which decree in 1966 abolished the regions and introduced provinces/states planning?",
        "options": [
            "Decree No. 20",
            "Decree No. 34",
            "Decree No. 8",
            "Decree No. 24"
        ],
        "answer": "Decree No. 34"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who served as Premier of the Northern Region in the 1950s and early 1960s?",
        "options": [
            "Ahmadu Bello",
            "Aminu Kano",
            "Shehu Shagari",
            "Abubakar Tafawa Balewa"
        ],
        "answer": "Ahmadu Bello"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who served as Premier of the Western Region in the 1950s?",
        "options": [
            "Ladoke Akintola",
            "Samuel Akintola",
            "Obafemi Awolowo",
            "Michael Ajasin"
        ],
        "answer": "Obafemi Awolowo"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who served as Premier of the Eastern Region in the early 1960s?",
        "options": [
            "Dennis Osadebay",
            "Nnamdi Azikiwe",
            "Kingsley Mbadiwe",
            "Michael Okpara"
        ],
        "answer": "Michael Okpara"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which Lagos-based political party emerged from the Nigerian Youth Movement split?",
        "options": [
            "AG",
            "NPC",
            "NCNC",
            "SDP"
        ],
        "answer": "NCNC"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which city hosted the 1958 Constitutional Conference that led to independence terms?",
        "options": [
            "Ibadan",
            "London",
            "Kaduna",
            "Lagos"
        ],
        "answer": "London"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which commission in 1958 reviewed Nigeria’s revenue allocation?",
        "options": [
            "Okigbo Commission",
            "Binns Commission",
            "Raisman Commission",
            "Hicks-Phillipson"
        ],
        "answer": "Raisman Commission"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which formula emphasized derivation principle before independence?",
        "options": [
            "Aboyade formula",
            "Dina formula",
            "Raisman formula",
            "Okigbo formula"
        ],
        "answer": "Raisman formula"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which tribunal tried the 1962 AG crisis cases?",
        "options": [
            "Oputa Panel",
            "Willink Commission",
            "Coker Commission",
            "Giwa Commission"
        ],
        "answer": "Coker Commission"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which 1958 commission studied minority fears before independence?",
        "options": [
            "Oputa Panel",
            "Coker Commission",
            "Cookey Commission",
            "Willink Commission"
        ],
        "answer": "Willink Commission"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which 1976 reform restructured local government nationwide?",
        "options": [
            "1988 Civil Service Reforms",
            "1963 LG Order",
            "1976 Local Government Reforms",
            "1999 LG Act"
        ],
        "answer": "1976 Local Government Reforms"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who led the January 1966 coup in Kaduna?",
        "options": [
            "Emeka Ojukwu",
            "Wale Ademoyega",
            "Chukwuma Kaduna Nzeogwu",
            "Yakubu Gowon"
        ],
        "answer": "Chukwuma Kaduna Nzeogwu"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where were the Aburi talks held in 1967?",
        "options": [
            "Ghana",
            "Kenya",
            "Nigeria",
            "Sierra Leone"
        ],
        "answer": "Ghana"
    },
    {
        "question": "What was the code name for the federal final offensive ending the Civil War?",
        "options": [
            "Operation Thunderbolt",
            "Operation Unity",
            "Operation Light",
            "Operation Tail-Wind"
        ],
        "answer": "Operation Tail-Wind"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who served as Biafra’s second-in-command and signed the surrender in 1970?",
        "options": [
            "Joseph Achuzia",
            "Emeka Ojukwu",
            "Philip Effiong",
            "Alexander Madiebo"
        ],
        "answer": "Philip Effiong"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which military ruler created 19 states in 1976?",
        "options": [
            "Murtala Mohammed",
            "Sani Abacha",
            "Ibrahim Babangida",
            "Yakubu Gowon"
        ],
        "answer": "Murtala Mohammed"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which military president created new states in 1987 and 1991?",
        "options": [
            "Ibrahim Babangida",
            "Sani Abacha",
            "Olusegun Obasanjo",
            "Yakubu Gowon"
        ],
        "answer": "Ibrahim Babangida"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which decree in 1978 replaced 'Nigeria, We Hail Thee' with a new anthem?",
        "options": [
            "Decree No. 1 of 1966",
            "Decree No. 24 of 1999",
            "Decree No. 8 of 1967",
            "Decree No. 33 of 1978"
        ],
        "answer": "Decree No. 33 of 1978"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which 1998–99 leader organized the transition to the Fourth Republic?",
        "options": [
            "Abdulsalami Abubakar",
            "Sani Abacha",
            "Ernest Shonekan",
            "Ibrahim Babangida"
        ],
        "answer": "Abdulsalami Abubakar"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which 1975 coup removed Yakubu Gowon?",
        "options": [
            "Benin mutiny",
            "Palace coup while Gowon was abroad",
            "Nzeogwu coup",
            "Bloody Lagos coup"
        ],
        "answer": "Palace coup while Gowon was abroad"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which 1985 coup brought Babangida to power?",
        "options": [
            "Dimka coup",
            "Langtang mutiny",
            "Gideon Orkar coup",
            "Buhari–Idiagbon overthrow"
        ],
        "answer": "Buhari–Idiagbon overthrow"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where was oil first discovered in commercial quantity in 1956?",
        "options": [
            "Bonny",
            "Forcados",
            "Oloibiri",
            "Warri"
        ],
        "answer": "Oloibiri"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which act nationalized parts of the oil industry in 1969?",
        "options": [
            "NNPC Act 1977",
            "Minerals Act 1958",
            "Petroleum Act 1969",
            "Local Content Act 2010"
        ],
        "answer": "Petroleum Act 1969"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which year did Nigeria join OPEC?",
        "options": [
            "1971",
            "1975",
            "1969",
            "1973"
        ],
        "answer": "1971"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which company became NNPC in 1977 after reorganization?",
        "options": [
            "NDDC",
            "NEPA",
            "NPC",
            "NNOC"
        ],
        "answer": "NNOC"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which refinery began operations in 1965?",
        "options": [
            "Port Harcourt Refinery",
            "Warri Refinery",
            "Kaduna Refinery",
            "Eleme Petrochemical"
        ],
        "answer": "Port Harcourt Refinery"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which UNESCO World Heritage Site was inscribed in 2005 in Osun State?",
        "options": [
            "Ogbunike Caves",
            "Ikom Monoliths",
            "Osun-Osogbo Sacred Grove",
            "Sukur"
        ],
        "answer": "Osun-Osogbo Sacred Grove"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which city is associated with ancient Ife bronze heads?",
        "options": [
            "Ile-Ife",
            "Zaria",
            "Katsina",
            "Benin City"
        ],
        "answer": "Ile-Ife"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Kiriji War (c. 1877–1893) was fought among which people?",
        "options": [
            "Igbo communities",
            "Yoruba subgroups",
            "Ijaw clans",
            "Hausa states"
        ],
        "answer": "Yoruba subgroups"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was Jaja of Opobo originally before founding Opobo?",
        "options": [
            "An Aro/Igbo trader (Umutong)",
            "A Nupe prince",
            "A Yoruba warrior",
            "A Bornu scholar"
        ],
        "answer": "An Aro/Igbo trader (Umutong)"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which emirate became prominent after Afonja’s fall in Ilorin?",
        "options": [
            "Kano Emirate",
            "Zaria Emirate",
            "Ilorin Emirate",
            "Katsina Emirate"
        ],
        "answer": "Ilorin Emirate"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which constitution introduced an American-style presidential system in Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "1963 Constitution",
            "1999 Constitution",
            "1989 Constitution",
            "1979 Constitution"
        ],
        "answer": "1979 Constitution"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which constitution currently governs Nigeria’s Fourth Republic?",
        "options": [
            "1979 Constitution",
            "1963 Constitution",
            "1989 Constitution",
            "1999 Constitution"
        ],
        "answer": "1999 Constitution"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which 1989 constitution was drafted but not fully implemented?",
        "options": [
            "1993 Transition Charter",
            "1989 Constitution",
            "1995 Draft",
            "1979 Constitution"
        ],
        "answer": "1989 Constitution"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which 1954 constitution entrenched federalism pre-independence?",
        "options": [
            "Richards (1946)",
            "Macpherson (1951)",
            "Clifford (1922)",
            "Lyttleton Constitution (1954)"
        ],
        "answer": "Lyttleton Constitution (1954)"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which commission investigated human rights abuses after 1999?",
        "options": [
            "Willink Commission",
            "Oputa Panel",
            "Okigbo Panel",
            "Coker Commission"
        ],
        "answer": "Oputa Panel"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was widely regarded as winner of the June 12, 1993 election?",
        "options": [
            "M.K.O. Abiola",
            "Shehu Yar’Adua",
            "Tunji Braithwaite",
            "Bashir Tofa"
        ],
        "answer": "M.K.O. Abiola"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who headed the Interim National Government in 1993?",
        "options": [
            "Alex Ekwueme",
            "Balarabe Musa",
            "Atiku Abubakar",
            "Ernest Shonekan"
        ],
        "answer": "Ernest Shonekan"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which general took power on November 17, 1993?",
        "options": [
            "Abdulsalami Abubakar",
            "Sani Abacha",
            "Olusegun Obasanjo",
            "Ibrahim Babangida"
        ],
        "answer": "Sani Abacha"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which year did Abacha die in office?",
        "options": [
            "1996",
            "1999",
            "1998",
            "1997"
        ],
        "answer": "1998"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who succeeded Abacha as Head of State?",
        "options": [
            "Ibrahim Babangida",
            "Olusegun Obasanjo",
            "Abdulsalami Abubakar",
            "Jeremiah Useni"
        ],
        "answer": "Abdulsalami Abubakar"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which university was founded by Nnamdi Azikiwe and opened in 1960?",
        "options": [
            "University of Lagos",
            "University of Nigeria, Nsukka",
            "ABU Zaria",
            "UniIbadan"
        ],
        "answer": "University of Nigeria, Nsukka"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which premier established the first television service in Africa (WNTV) in 1959?",
        "options": [
            "Obafemi Awolowo",
            "Ahmadu Bello",
            "Nnamdi Azikiwe",
            "Michael Okpara"
        ],
        "answer": "Obafemi Awolowo"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which newspaper did Awolowo establish in 1949?",
        "options": [
            "Nigerian Tribune",
            "Daily Times",
            "The Nation",
            "Pilot"
        ],
        "answer": "Nigerian Tribune"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which federal capital development authority was set up in the 1970s for Abuja?",
        "options": [
            "NDA",
            "FCTA",
            "FRCN",
            "FCDA"
        ],
        "answer": "FCDA"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which commission managed revenue allocation in the oil boom of the 1970s?",
        "options": [
            "Dina Commission",
            "Okigbo Commission",
            "Raisman Commission",
            "Aboyade Committee"
        ],
        "answer": "Okigbo Commission"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which year saw Nigeria’s first military coup?",
        "options": [
            "1966",
            "1967",
            "1975",
            "1983"
        ],
        "answer": "1966"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which year did the military overthrow Shagari’s government?",
        "options": [
            "1985",
            "1983",
            "1979",
            "1993"
        ],
        "answer": "1983"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which year did Buhari get overthrown by Babangida?",
        "options": [
            "1987",
            "1985",
            "1991",
            "1983"
        ],
        "answer": "1985"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which year did Obasanjo hand over to Shagari?",
        "options": [
            "1979",
            "1999",
            "1976",
            "1983"
        ],
        "answer": "1979"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which year did Abdulsalami Abubakar hand over to civilians?",
        "options": [
            "2003",
            "1998",
            "1999",
            "1996"
        ],
        "answer": "1999"
    },
    {
        "question": "Kanem-Bornu reached a peak under which ruler?",
        "options": [
            "Mai Idris Alooma",
            "Aminu Kano",
            "Mai Dunama Dabbalemi",
            "Uthman Ali"
        ],
        "answer": "Mai Idris Alooma"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which Fulani jihad leader established the Sokoto Caliphate’s emirate system?",
        "options": [
            "Abdullahi dan Fodio",
            "Muhammad Bello",
            "Usman dan Fodio",
            "Ahmadu Rufai"
        ],
        "answer": "Usman dan Fodio"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which Benin Oba expanded trade with the Portuguese in the 15th–16th centuries?",
        "options": [
            "Oba Ewuare II",
            "Oba Ovonramwen",
            "Oba Akenzua II",
            "Oba Esigie"
        ],
        "answer": "Oba Esigie"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which Yoruba state was famous for cavalry and long-distance trade?",
        "options": [
            "Ijebu Kingdom",
            "Ibadan polity",
            "Oyo Empire",
            "Ife Kingdom"
        ],
        "answer": "Oyo Empire"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Nupe Kingdom was centered along which river?",
        "options": [
            "Osun",
            "Niger",
            "Cross",
            "Benue"
        ],
        "answer": "Niger"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which commission in 1957–58 examined minority fears in Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Willink Commission",
            "Okigbo Commission",
            "Oputa Panel",
            "Coker Commission"
        ],
        "answer": "Willink Commission"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which policy promoted indigenization in the 1970s?",
        "options": [
            "Green Revolution",
            "Nigerian Enterprises Promotion Decrees",
            "Structural Adjustment Programme",
            "Operation Feed the Nation"
        ],
        "answer": "Nigerian Enterprises Promotion Decrees"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which program launched under Obasanjo in 1976 targeted agriculture?",
        "options": [
            "Green Revolution",
            "Better Life for Rural Women",
            "Operation Feed the Nation",
            "SAP"
        ],
        "answer": "Operation Feed the Nation"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which program launched under Shagari in 1980 focused on agriculture?",
        "options": [
            "Operation Feed the Nation",
            "Vision 2010",
            "Green Revolution",
            "OFN"
        ],
        "answer": "Green Revolution"
    },
    {
        "question": "What was the name of the 1986 economic policy under Babangida?",
        "options": [
            "Structural Adjustment Programme",
            "Seven-Point Agenda",
            "Vision 2010",
            "NEEDS"
        ],
        "answer": "Structural Adjustment Programme"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which leader created the Federal Capital Territory in 1976?",
        "options": [
            "Olusegun Obasanjo",
            "Yakubu Gowon",
            "Ibrahim Babangida",
            "Murtala Mohammed"
        ],
        "answer": "Murtala Mohammed"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which 1953 motion controversy led to the Kano riots?",
        "options": [
            "Enahoro’s self-government motion",
            "Willink report",
            "Macpherson debate",
            "Richards reforms"
        ],
        "answer": "Enahoro’s self-government motion"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which northern politician was assassinated during the January 1966 coup?",
        "options": [
            "Muhammadu Ribadu",
            "Aminu Kano",
            "Ahmadu Bello",
            "Abubakar Tafawa Balewa"
        ],
        "answer": "Ahmadu Bello"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which law in 1978 reformed land ownership?",
        "options": [
            "Land Use Decree (Act) 1978",
            "Public Lands Act 1918",
            "Minerals Act 1958",
            "FOI Act 2011"
        ],
        "answer": "Land Use Decree (Act) 1978"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which body conducted the 1979 elections?",
        "options": [
            "FEDECO",
            "INEC",
            "NEC",
            "SIEC"
        ],
        "answer": "FEDECO"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which decree established NNPC in 1977?",
        "options": [
            "NNPC Act 1977",
            "NDDC Act 2000",
            "Minerals Act 1958",
            "Petroleum Act 1969"
        ],
        "answer": "NNPC Act 1977"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which organization managed political parties’ registration in 1979 era?",
        "options": [
            "FEDECO",
            "INEC",
            "SIEC",
            "NEC"
        ],
        "answer": "FEDECO"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which conference laid foundations for independence in 1957–58?",
        "options": [
            "Enugu Roundtable",
            "Kano Congress",
            "London Constitutional Conferences",
            "Accra Talks"
        ],
        "answer": "London Constitutional Conferences"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which city was capital of Western Region?",
        "options": [
            "Abeokuta",
            "Ife",
            "Akure",
            "Ibadan"
        ],
        "answer": "Ibadan"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which year was the Mid-Western Region carved out?",
        "options": [
            "1960",
            "1967",
            "1957",
            "1963"
        ],
        "answer": "1963"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which city was seat of Northern Region government before 1967?",
        "options": [
            "Kaduna",
            "Zaria",
            "Kano",
            "Jos"
        ],
        "answer": "Kaduna"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which leader announced Nigeria’s 12-state structure in May 1967?",
        "options": [
            "Murtala Mohammed",
            "Obasanjo",
            "Yakubu Gowon",
            "Aguiyi-Ironsi"
        ],
        "answer": "Yakubu Gowon"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which city was capital of Eastern Region?",
        "options": [
            "Aba",
            "Calabar",
            "Enugu",
            "Onitsha"
        ],
        "answer": "Enugu"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what year did Nigeria gain independence?",
        "options": [
            "1960",
            "1961",
            "1963",
            "1959"
        ],
        "answer": "1960"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was the first Nigerian Prime Minister?",
        "options": [
            "Ahmadu Bello",
            "Tafawa Balewa",
            "Obafemi Awolowo",
            "Nnamdi Azikiwe"
        ],
        "answer": "Tafawa Balewa"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who amalgamated Northern and Southern Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Lord Lugard",
            "Arthur Richards",
            "John Macpherson",
            "Hugh Clifford"
        ],
        "answer": "Lord Lugard"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which war lasted from 1967 to 1970 in Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Kiriji War",
            "Ekumeku War",
            "Nigerian Civil War",
            "Yoruba Civil War"
        ],
        "answer": "Nigerian Civil War"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which constitution took effect in 1999?",
        "options": [
            "1999 Constitution",
            "Independence Constitution",
            "1979 Constitution",
            "1963 Constitution"
        ],
        "answer": "1999 Constitution"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what year did Nigeria gain independence?",
        "options": [
            "1960",
            "1961",
            "1959",
            "1963"
        ],
        "answer": "1960"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was the first Nigerian Prime Minister?",
        "options": [
            "Tafawa Balewa",
            "Nnamdi Azikiwe",
            "Obafemi Awolowo",
            "Ahmadu Bello"
        ],
        "answer": "Tafawa Balewa"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who amalgamated Northern and Southern Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Arthur Richards",
            "Lord Lugard",
            "John Macpherson",
            "Hugh Clifford"
        ],
        "answer": "Lord Lugard"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which war lasted from 1967 to 1970 in Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Ekumeku War",
            "Yoruba Civil War",
            "Kiriji War",
            "Nigerian Civil War"
        ],
        "answer": "Nigerian Civil War"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which constitution took effect in 1999?",
        "options": [
            "1963 Constitution",
            "1979 Constitution",
            "1999 Constitution",
            "Independence Constitution"
        ],
        "answer": "1999 Constitution"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what year did Nigeria gain independence?",
        "options": [
            "1961",
            "1963",
            "1959",
            "1960"
        ],
        "answer": "1960"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was the first Nigerian Prime Minister?",
        "options": [
            "Nnamdi Azikiwe",
            "Obafemi Awolowo",
            "Tafawa Balewa",
            "Ahmadu Bello"
        ],
        "answer": "Tafawa Balewa"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who amalgamated Northern and Southern Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "John Macpherson",
            "Hugh Clifford",
            "Arthur Richards",
            "Lord Lugard"
        ],
        "answer": "Lord Lugard"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which war lasted from 1967 to 1970 in Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Nigerian Civil War",
            "Yoruba Civil War",
            "Kiriji War",
            "Ekumeku War"
        ],
        "answer": "Nigerian Civil War"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which constitution took effect in 1999?",
        "options": [
            "1999 Constitution",
            "Independence Constitution",
            "1963 Constitution",
            "1979 Constitution"
        ],
        "answer": "1999 Constitution"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what year did Nigeria gain independence?",
        "options": [
            "1959",
            "1960",
            "1963",
            "1961"
        ],
        "answer": "1960"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was the first Nigerian Prime Minister?",
        "options": [
            "Nnamdi Azikiwe",
            "Tafawa Balewa",
            "Ahmadu Bello",
            "Obafemi Awolowo"
        ],
        "answer": "Tafawa Balewa"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who amalgamated Northern and Southern Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Arthur Richards",
            "Hugh Clifford",
            "John Macpherson",
            "Lord Lugard"
        ],
        "answer": "Lord Lugard"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which war lasted from 1967 to 1970 in Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Kiriji War",
            "Yoruba Civil War",
            "Ekumeku War",
            "Nigerian Civil War"
        ],
        "answer": "Nigerian Civil War"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which constitution took effect in 1999?",
        "options": [
            "1963 Constitution",
            "1979 Constitution",
            "Independence Constitution",
            "1999 Constitution"
        ],
        "answer": "1999 Constitution"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what year did Nigeria gain independence?",
        "options": [
            "1961",
            "1959",
            "1960",
            "1963"
        ],
        "answer": "1960"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was the first Nigerian Prime Minister?",
        "options": [
            "Nnamdi Azikiwe",
            "Ahmadu Bello",
            "Obafemi Awolowo",
            "Tafawa Balewa"
        ],
        "answer": "Tafawa Balewa"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who amalgamated Northern and Southern Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Lord Lugard",
            "John Macpherson",
            "Hugh Clifford",
            "Arthur Richards"
        ],
        "answer": "Lord Lugard"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which war lasted from 1967 to 1970 in Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Ekumeku War",
            "Kiriji War",
            "Yoruba Civil War",
            "Nigerian Civil War"
        ],
        "answer": "Nigerian Civil War"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which constitution took effect in 1999?",
        "options": [
            "Independence Constitution",
            "1999 Constitution",
            "1979 Constitution",
            "1963 Constitution"
        ],
        "answer": "1999 Constitution"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what year did Nigeria gain independence?",
        "options": [
            "1961",
            "1960",
            "1963",
            "1959"
        ],
        "answer": "1960"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was the first Nigerian Prime Minister?",
        "options": [
            "Tafawa Balewa",
            "Ahmadu Bello",
            "Obafemi Awolowo",
            "Nnamdi Azikiwe"
        ],
        "answer": "Tafawa Balewa"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who amalgamated Northern and Southern Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "John Macpherson",
            "Arthur Richards",
            "Lord Lugard",
            "Hugh Clifford"
        ],
        "answer": "Lord Lugard"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which war lasted from 1967 to 1970 in Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Ekumeku War",
            "Nigerian Civil War",
            "Kiriji War",
            "Yoruba Civil War"
        ],
        "answer": "Nigerian Civil War"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which constitution took effect in 1999?",
        "options": [
            "1999 Constitution",
            "1979 Constitution",
            "Independence Constitution",
            "1963 Constitution"
        ],
        "answer": "1999 Constitution"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what year did Nigeria gain independence?",
        "options": [
            "1961",
            "1963",
            "1959",
            "1960"
        ],
        "answer": "1960"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was the first Nigerian Prime Minister?",
        "options": [
            "Obafemi Awolowo",
            "Tafawa Balewa",
            "Nnamdi Azikiwe",
            "Ahmadu Bello"
        ],
        "answer": "Tafawa Balewa"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who amalgamated Northern and Southern Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Arthur Richards",
            "Lord Lugard",
            "Hugh Clifford",
            "John Macpherson"
        ],
        "answer": "Lord Lugard"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which war lasted from 1967 to 1970 in Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Ekumeku War",
            "Kiriji War",
            "Yoruba Civil War",
            "Nigerian Civil War"
        ],
        "answer": "Nigerian Civil War"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which constitution took effect in 1999?",
        "options": [
            "Independence Constitution",
            "1999 Constitution",
            "1963 Constitution",
            "1979 Constitution"
        ],
        "answer": "1999 Constitution"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what year did Nigeria gain independence?",
        "options": [
            "1959",
            "1963",
            "1960",
            "1961"
        ],
        "answer": "1960"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was the first Nigerian Prime Minister?",
        "options": [
            "Ahmadu Bello",
            "Tafawa Balewa",
            "Nnamdi Azikiwe",
            "Obafemi Awolowo"
        ],
        "answer": "Tafawa Balewa"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who amalgamated Northern and Southern Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "John Macpherson",
            "Arthur Richards",
            "Lord Lugard",
            "Hugh Clifford"
        ],
        "answer": "Lord Lugard"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which war lasted from 1967 to 1970 in Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Nigerian Civil War",
            "Ekumeku War",
            "Kiriji War",
            "Yoruba Civil War"
        ],
        "answer": "Nigerian Civil War"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which constitution took effect in 1999?",
        "options": [
            "1963 Constitution",
            "1979 Constitution",
            "1999 Constitution",
            "Independence Constitution"
        ],
        "answer": "1999 Constitution"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what year did Nigeria gain independence?",
        "options": [
            "1963",
            "1960",
            "1961",
            "1959"
        ],
        "answer": "1960"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was the first Nigerian Prime Minister?",
        "options": [
            "Ahmadu Bello",
            "Nnamdi Azikiwe",
            "Tafawa Balewa",
            "Obafemi Awolowo"
        ],
        "answer": "Tafawa Balewa"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who amalgamated Northern and Southern Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "John Macpherson",
            "Arthur Richards",
            "Hugh Clifford",
            "Lord Lugard"
        ],
        "answer": "Lord Lugard"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which war lasted from 1967 to 1970 in Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Ekumeku War",
            "Kiriji War",
            "Yoruba Civil War",
            "Nigerian Civil War"
        ],
        "answer": "Nigerian Civil War"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which constitution took effect in 1999?",
        "options": [
            "1979 Constitution",
            "1999 Constitution",
            "Independence Constitution",
            "1963 Constitution"
        ],
        "answer": "1999 Constitution"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what year did Nigeria gain independence?",
        "options": [
            "1959",
            "1961",
            "1963",
            "1960"
        ],
        "answer": "1960"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was the first Nigerian Prime Minister?",
        "options": [
            "Nnamdi Azikiwe",
            "Obafemi Awolowo",
            "Ahmadu Bello",
            "Tafawa Balewa"
        ],
        "answer": "Tafawa Balewa"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who amalgamated Northern and Southern Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Arthur Richards",
            "John Macpherson",
            "Hugh Clifford",
            "Lord Lugard"
        ],
        "answer": "Lord Lugard"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which war lasted from 1967 to 1970 in Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Ekumeku War",
            "Kiriji War",
            "Yoruba Civil War",
            "Nigerian Civil War"
        ],
        "answer": "Nigerian Civil War"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which constitution took effect in 1999?",
        "options": [
            "1963 Constitution",
            "Independence Constitution",
            "1999 Constitution",
            "1979 Constitution"
        ],
        "answer": "1999 Constitution"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what year did Nigeria gain independence?",
        "options": [
            "1963",
            "1960",
            "1959",
            "1961"
        ],
        "answer": "1960"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was the first Nigerian Prime Minister?",
        "options": [
            "Obafemi Awolowo",
            "Tafawa Balewa",
            "Nnamdi Azikiwe",
            "Ahmadu Bello"
        ],
        "answer": "Tafawa Balewa"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who amalgamated Northern and Southern Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Arthur Richards",
            "Lord Lugard",
            "Hugh Clifford",
            "John Macpherson"
        ],
        "answer": "Lord Lugard"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which war lasted from 1967 to 1970 in Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Ekumeku War",
            "Nigerian Civil War",
            "Yoruba Civil War",
            "Kiriji War"
        ],
        "answer": "Nigerian Civil War"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which constitution took effect in 1999?",
        "options": [
            "Independence Constitution",
            "1979 Constitution",
            "1999 Constitution",
            "1963 Constitution"
        ],
        "answer": "1999 Constitution"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what year did Nigeria gain independence?",
        "options": [
            "1963",
            "1961",
            "1959",
            "1960"
        ],
        "answer": "1960"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was the first Nigerian Prime Minister?",
        "options": [
            "Ahmadu Bello",
            "Tafawa Balewa",
            "Obafemi Awolowo",
            "Nnamdi Azikiwe"
        ],
        "answer": "Tafawa Balewa"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who amalgamated Northern and Southern Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "John Macpherson",
            "Lord Lugard",
            "Hugh Clifford",
            "Arthur Richards"
        ],
        "answer": "Lord Lugard"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which war lasted from 1967 to 1970 in Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Yoruba Civil War",
            "Kiriji War",
            "Nigerian Civil War",
            "Ekumeku War"
        ],
        "answer": "Nigerian Civil War"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which constitution took effect in 1999?",
        "options": [
            "Independence Constitution",
            "1979 Constitution",
            "1963 Constitution",
            "1999 Constitution"
        ],
        "answer": "1999 Constitution"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what year did Nigeria gain independence?",
        "options": [
            "1960",
            "1959",
            "1961",
            "1963"
        ],
        "answer": "1960"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was the first Nigerian Prime Minister?",
        "options": [
            "Tafawa Balewa",
            "Obafemi Awolowo",
            "Ahmadu Bello",
            "Nnamdi Azikiwe"
        ],
        "answer": "Tafawa Balewa"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who amalgamated Northern and Southern Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Lord Lugard",
            "Hugh Clifford",
            "John Macpherson",
            "Arthur Richards"
        ],
        "answer": "Lord Lugard"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which war lasted from 1967 to 1970 in Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Kiriji War",
            "Ekumeku War",
            "Nigerian Civil War",
            "Yoruba Civil War"
        ],
        "answer": "Nigerian Civil War"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which constitution took effect in 1999?",
        "options": [
            "1979 Constitution",
            "1963 Constitution",
            "1999 Constitution",
            "Independence Constitution"
        ],
        "answer": "1999 Constitution"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what year did Nigeria gain independence?",
        "options": [
            "1963",
            "1959",
            "1960",
            "1961"
        ],
        "answer": "1960"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was the first Nigerian Prime Minister?",
        "options": [
            "Ahmadu Bello",
            "Obafemi Awolowo",
            "Nnamdi Azikiwe",
            "Tafawa Balewa"
        ],
        "answer": "Tafawa Balewa"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who amalgamated Northern and Southern Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "John Macpherson",
            "Arthur Richards",
            "Lord Lugard",
            "Hugh Clifford"
        ],
        "answer": "Lord Lugard"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which war lasted from 1967 to 1970 in Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Nigerian Civil War",
            "Ekumeku War",
            "Yoruba Civil War",
            "Kiriji War"
        ],
        "answer": "Nigerian Civil War"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which constitution took effect in 1999?",
        "options": [
            "1963 Constitution",
            "1999 Constitution",
            "1979 Constitution",
            "Independence Constitution"
        ],
        "answer": "1999 Constitution"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what year did Nigeria gain independence?",
        "options": [
            "1963",
            "1960",
            "1961",
            "1959"
        ],
        "answer": "1960"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was the first Nigerian Prime Minister?",
        "options": [
            "Tafawa Balewa",
            "Nnamdi Azikiwe",
            "Ahmadu Bello",
            "Obafemi Awolowo"
        ],
        "answer": "Tafawa Balewa"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who amalgamated Northern and Southern Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Lord Lugard",
            "Arthur Richards",
            "John Macpherson",
            "Hugh Clifford"
        ],
        "answer": "Lord Lugard"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which war lasted from 1967 to 1970 in Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Kiriji War",
            "Nigerian Civil War",
            "Ekumeku War",
            "Yoruba Civil War"
        ],
        "answer": "Nigerian Civil War"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which constitution took effect in 1999?",
        "options": [
            "1963 Constitution",
            "1999 Constitution",
            "Independence Constitution",
            "1979 Constitution"
        ],
        "answer": "1999 Constitution"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what year did Nigeria gain independence?",
        "options": [
            "1959",
            "1960",
            "1963",
            "1961"
        ],
        "answer": "1960"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was the first Nigerian Prime Minister?",
        "options": [
            "Obafemi Awolowo",
            "Tafawa Balewa",
            "Nnamdi Azikiwe",
            "Ahmadu Bello"
        ],
        "answer": "Tafawa Balewa"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who amalgamated Northern and Southern Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "John Macpherson",
            "Lord Lugard",
            "Arthur Richards",
            "Hugh Clifford"
        ],
        "answer": "Lord Lugard"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which war lasted from 1967 to 1970 in Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Yoruba Civil War",
            "Kiriji War",
            "Ekumeku War",
            "Nigerian Civil War"
        ],
        "answer": "Nigerian Civil War"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which constitution took effect in 1999?",
        "options": [
            "1999 Constitution",
            "1963 Constitution",
            "1979 Constitution",
            "Independence Constitution"
        ],
        "answer": "1999 Constitution"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what year did Nigeria gain independence?",
        "options": [
            "1960",
            "1961",
            "1963",
            "1959"
        ],
        "answer": "1960"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was the first Nigerian Prime Minister?",
        "options": [
            "Obafemi Awolowo",
            "Ahmadu Bello",
            "Nnamdi Azikiwe",
            "Tafawa Balewa"
        ],
        "answer": "Tafawa Balewa"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who amalgamated Northern and Southern Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Lord Lugard",
            "John Macpherson",
            "Hugh Clifford",
            "Arthur Richards"
        ],
        "answer": "Lord Lugard"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which war lasted from 1967 to 1970 in Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Nigerian Civil War",
            "Kiriji War",
            "Ekumeku War",
            "Yoruba Civil War"
        ],
        "answer": "Nigerian Civil War"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which constitution took effect in 1999?",
        "options": [
            "1999 Constitution",
            "1979 Constitution",
            "1963 Constitution",
            "Independence Constitution"
        ],
        "answer": "1999 Constitution"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what year did Nigeria gain independence?",
        "options": [
            "1961",
            "1960",
            "1959",
            "1963"
        ],
        "answer": "1960"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was the first Nigerian Prime Minister?",
        "options": [
            "Obafemi Awolowo",
            "Nnamdi Azikiwe",
            "Tafawa Balewa",
            "Ahmadu Bello"
        ],
        "answer": "Tafawa Balewa"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who amalgamated Northern and Southern Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Arthur Richards",
            "John Macpherson",
            "Hugh Clifford",
            "Lord Lugard"
        ],
        "answer": "Lord Lugard"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which war lasted from 1967 to 1970 in Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Yoruba Civil War",
            "Ekumeku War",
            "Kiriji War",
            "Nigerian Civil War"
        ],
        "answer": "Nigerian Civil War"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which constitution took effect in 1999?",
        "options": [
            "1979 Constitution",
            "1999 Constitution",
            "1963 Constitution",
            "Independence Constitution"
        ],
        "answer": "1999 Constitution"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what year did Nigeria gain independence?",
        "options": [
            "1959",
            "1961",
            "1960",
            "1963"
        ],
        "answer": "1960"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was the first Nigerian Prime Minister?",
        "options": [
            "Obafemi Awolowo",
            "Tafawa Balewa",
            "Ahmadu Bello",
            "Nnamdi Azikiwe"
        ],
        "answer": "Tafawa Balewa"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who amalgamated Northern and Southern Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "John Macpherson",
            "Hugh Clifford",
            "Arthur Richards",
            "Lord Lugard"
        ],
        "answer": "Lord Lugard"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which war lasted from 1967 to 1970 in Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Yoruba Civil War",
            "Kiriji War",
            "Ekumeku War",
            "Nigerian Civil War"
        ],
        "answer": "Nigerian Civil War"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which constitution took effect in 1999?",
        "options": [
            "1979 Constitution",
            "1999 Constitution",
            "Independence Constitution",
            "1963 Constitution"
        ],
        "answer": "1999 Constitution"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what year did Nigeria gain independence?",
        "options": [
            "1959",
            "1961",
            "1960",
            "1963"
        ],
        "answer": "1960"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was the first Nigerian Prime Minister?",
        "options": [
            "Ahmadu Bello",
            "Tafawa Balewa",
            "Nnamdi Azikiwe",
            "Obafemi Awolowo"
        ],
        "answer": "Tafawa Balewa"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who amalgamated Northern and Southern Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Hugh Clifford",
            "John Macpherson",
            "Arthur Richards",
            "Lord Lugard"
        ],
        "answer": "Lord Lugard"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which war lasted from 1967 to 1970 in Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Kiriji War",
            "Yoruba Civil War",
            "Ekumeku War",
            "Nigerian Civil War"
        ],
        "answer": "Nigerian Civil War"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which constitution took effect in 1999?",
        "options": [
            "1979 Constitution",
            "1999 Constitution",
            "1963 Constitution",
            "Independence Constitution"
        ],
        "answer": "1999 Constitution"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what year did Nigeria gain independence?",
        "options": [
            "1961",
            "1959",
            "1963",
            "1960"
        ],
        "answer": "1960"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was the first Nigerian Prime Minister?",
        "options": [
            "Obafemi Awolowo",
            "Nnamdi Azikiwe",
            "Tafawa Balewa",
            "Ahmadu Bello"
        ],
        "answer": "Tafawa Balewa"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who amalgamated Northern and Southern Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "John Macpherson",
            "Hugh Clifford",
            "Arthur Richards",
            "Lord Lugard"
        ],
        "answer": "Lord Lugard"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which war lasted from 1967 to 1970 in Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Yoruba Civil War",
            "Kiriji War",
            "Nigerian Civil War",
            "Ekumeku War"
        ],
        "answer": "Nigerian Civil War"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which constitution took effect in 1999?",
        "options": [
            "1979 Constitution",
            "Independence Constitution",
            "1999 Constitution",
            "1963 Constitution"
        ],
        "answer": "1999 Constitution"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what year did Nigeria gain independence?",
        "options": [
            "1960",
            "1961",
            "1963",
            "1959"
        ],
        "answer": "1960"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was the first Nigerian Prime Minister?",
        "options": [
            "Obafemi Awolowo",
            "Nnamdi Azikiwe",
            "Ahmadu Bello",
            "Tafawa Balewa"
        ],
        "answer": "Tafawa Balewa"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who amalgamated Northern and Southern Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "John Macpherson",
            "Arthur Richards",
            "Lord Lugard",
            "Hugh Clifford"
        ],
        "answer": "Lord Lugard"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which war lasted from 1967 to 1970 in Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Nigerian Civil War",
            "Yoruba Civil War",
            "Kiriji War",
            "Ekumeku War"
        ],
        "answer": "Nigerian Civil War"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which constitution took effect in 1999?",
        "options": [
            "Independence Constitution",
            "1963 Constitution",
            "1979 Constitution",
            "1999 Constitution"
        ],
        "answer": "1999 Constitution"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what year did Nigeria gain independence?",
        "options": [
            "1959",
            "1961",
            "1960",
            "1963"
        ],
        "answer": "1960"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was the first Nigerian Prime Minister?",
        "options": [
            "Ahmadu Bello",
            "Nnamdi Azikiwe",
            "Obafemi Awolowo",
            "Tafawa Balewa"
        ],
        "answer": "Tafawa Balewa"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who amalgamated Northern and Southern Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Lord Lugard",
            "Hugh Clifford",
            "Arthur Richards",
            "John Macpherson"
        ],
        "answer": "Lord Lugard"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which war lasted from 1967 to 1970 in Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Kiriji War",
            "Nigerian Civil War",
            "Yoruba Civil War",
            "Ekumeku War"
        ],
        "answer": "Nigerian Civil War"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which constitution took effect in 1999?",
        "options": [
            "1999 Constitution",
            "1963 Constitution",
            "1979 Constitution",
            "Independence Constitution"
        ],
        "answer": "1999 Constitution"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what year did Nigeria gain independence?",
        "options": [
            "1963",
            "1959",
            "1960",
            "1961"
        ],
        "answer": "1960"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was the first Nigerian Prime Minister?",
        "options": [
            "Obafemi Awolowo",
            "Tafawa Balewa",
            "Nnamdi Azikiwe",
            "Ahmadu Bello"
        ],
        "answer": "Tafawa Balewa"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who amalgamated Northern and Southern Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Lord Lugard",
            "John Macpherson",
            "Hugh Clifford",
            "Arthur Richards"
        ],
        "answer": "Lord Lugard"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which war lasted from 1967 to 1970 in Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Ekumeku War",
            "Nigerian Civil War",
            "Kiriji War",
            "Yoruba Civil War"
        ],
        "answer": "Nigerian Civil War"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which constitution took effect in 1999?",
        "options": [
            "Independence Constitution",
            "1963 Constitution",
            "1979 Constitution",
            "1999 Constitution"
        ],
        "answer": "1999 Constitution"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what year did Nigeria gain independence?",
        "options": [
            "1960",
            "1963",
            "1959",
            "1961"
        ],
        "answer": "1960"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was the first Nigerian Prime Minister?",
        "options": [
            "Ahmadu Bello",
            "Tafawa Balewa",
            "Obafemi Awolowo",
            "Nnamdi Azikiwe"
        ],
        "answer": "Tafawa Balewa"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who amalgamated Northern and Southern Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "John Macpherson",
            "Lord Lugard",
            "Hugh Clifford",
            "Arthur Richards"
        ],
        "answer": "Lord Lugard"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which war lasted from 1967 to 1970 in Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Yoruba Civil War",
            "Kiriji War",
            "Nigerian Civil War",
            "Ekumeku War"
        ],
        "answer": "Nigerian Civil War"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which constitution took effect in 1999?",
        "options": [
            "Independence Constitution",
            "1979 Constitution",
            "1999 Constitution",
            "1963 Constitution"
        ],
        "answer": "1999 Constitution"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what year did Nigeria gain independence?",
        "options": [
            "1961",
            "1959",
            "1960",
            "1963"
        ],
        "answer": "1960"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was the first Nigerian Prime Minister?",
        "options": [
            "Tafawa Balewa",
            "Nnamdi Azikiwe",
            "Ahmadu Bello",
            "Obafemi Awolowo"
        ],
        "answer": "Tafawa Balewa"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who amalgamated Northern and Southern Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Arthur Richards",
            "John Macpherson",
            "Hugh Clifford",
            "Lord Lugard"
        ],
        "answer": "Lord Lugard"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which war lasted from 1967 to 1970 in Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Ekumeku War",
            "Yoruba Civil War",
            "Kiriji War",
            "Nigerian Civil War"
        ],
        "answer": "Nigerian Civil War"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which constitution took effect in 1999?",
        "options": [
            "1979 Constitution",
            "1963 Constitution",
            "1999 Constitution",
            "Independence Constitution"
        ],
        "answer": "1999 Constitution"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what year did Nigeria gain independence?",
        "options": [
            "1963",
            "1961",
            "1960",
            "1959"
        ],
        "answer": "1960"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was the first Nigerian Prime Minister?",
        "options": [
            "Nnamdi Azikiwe",
            "Ahmadu Bello",
            "Obafemi Awolowo",
            "Tafawa Balewa"
        ],
        "answer": "Tafawa Balewa"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who amalgamated Northern and Southern Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "John Macpherson",
            "Arthur Richards",
            "Hugh Clifford",
            "Lord Lugard"
        ],
        "answer": "Lord Lugard"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which war lasted from 1967 to 1970 in Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Kiriji War",
            "Ekumeku War",
            "Yoruba Civil War",
            "Nigerian Civil War"
        ],
        "answer": "Nigerian Civil War"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which constitution took effect in 1999?",
        "options": [
            "1979 Constitution",
            "Independence Constitution",
            "1999 Constitution",
            "1963 Constitution"
        ],
        "answer": "1999 Constitution"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what year did Nigeria gain independence?",
        "options": [
            "1961",
            "1963",
            "1959",
            "1960"
        ],
        "answer": "1960"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was the first Nigerian Prime Minister?",
        "options": [
            "Ahmadu Bello",
            "Obafemi Awolowo",
            "Tafawa Balewa",
            "Nnamdi Azikiwe"
        ],
        "answer": "Tafawa Balewa"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who amalgamated Northern and Southern Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "John Macpherson",
            "Arthur Richards",
            "Hugh Clifford",
            "Lord Lugard"
        ],
        "answer": "Lord Lugard"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which war lasted from 1967 to 1970 in Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Kiriji War",
            "Yoruba Civil War",
            "Ekumeku War",
            "Nigerian Civil War"
        ],
        "answer": "Nigerian Civil War"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which constitution took effect in 1999?",
        "options": [
            "1963 Constitution",
            "1999 Constitution",
            "1979 Constitution",
            "Independence Constitution"
        ],
        "answer": "1999 Constitution"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what year did Nigeria gain independence?",
        "options": [
            "1961",
            "1960",
            "1959",
            "1963"
        ],
        "answer": "1960"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was the first Nigerian Prime Minister?",
        "options": [
            "Ahmadu Bello",
            "Tafawa Balewa",
            "Nnamdi Azikiwe",
            "Obafemi Awolowo"
        ],
        "answer": "Tafawa Balewa"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who amalgamated Northern and Southern Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Arthur Richards",
            "Lord Lugard",
            "Hugh Clifford",
            "John Macpherson"
        ],
        "answer": "Lord Lugard"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which war lasted from 1967 to 1970 in Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Kiriji War",
            "Ekumeku War",
            "Yoruba Civil War",
            "Nigerian Civil War"
        ],
        "answer": "Nigerian Civil War"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which constitution took effect in 1999?",
        "options": [
            "Independence Constitution",
            "1979 Constitution",
            "1999 Constitution",
            "1963 Constitution"
        ],
        "answer": "1999 Constitution"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what year did Nigeria gain independence?",
        "options": [
            "1963",
            "1961",
            "1960",
            "1959"
        ],
        "answer": "1960"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was the first Nigerian Prime Minister?",
        "options": [
            "Tafawa Balewa",
            "Obafemi Awolowo",
            "Nnamdi Azikiwe",
            "Ahmadu Bello"
        ],
        "answer": "Tafawa Balewa"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who amalgamated Northern and Southern Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "John Macpherson",
            "Hugh Clifford",
            "Lord Lugard",
            "Arthur Richards"
        ],
        "answer": "Lord Lugard"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which war lasted from 1967 to 1970 in Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Ekumeku War",
            "Yoruba Civil War",
            "Kiriji War",
            "Nigerian Civil War"
        ],
        "answer": "Nigerian Civil War"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which constitution took effect in 1999?",
        "options": [
            "1999 Constitution",
            "1979 Constitution",
            "Independence Constitution",
            "1963 Constitution"
        ],
        "answer": "1999 Constitution"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what year did Nigeria gain independence?",
        "options": [
            "1959",
            "1963",
            "1961",
            "1960"
        ],
        "answer": "1960"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was the first Nigerian Prime Minister?",
        "options": [
            "Tafawa Balewa",
            "Ahmadu Bello",
            "Obafemi Awolowo",
            "Nnamdi Azikiwe"
        ],
        "answer": "Tafawa Balewa"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who amalgamated Northern and Southern Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Arthur Richards",
            "Hugh Clifford",
            "John Macpherson",
            "Lord Lugard"
        ],
        "answer": "Lord Lugard"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which war lasted from 1967 to 1970 in Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Nigerian Civil War",
            "Yoruba Civil War",
            "Ekumeku War",
            "Kiriji War"
        ],
        "answer": "Nigerian Civil War"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which constitution took effect in 1999?",
        "options": [
            "1979 Constitution",
            "1963 Constitution",
            "Independence Constitution",
            "1999 Constitution"
        ],
        "answer": "1999 Constitution"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what year did Nigeria gain independence?",
        "options": [
            "1963",
            "1959",
            "1961",
            "1960"
        ],
        "answer": "1960"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was the first Nigerian Prime Minister?",
        "options": [
            "Nnamdi Azikiwe",
            "Ahmadu Bello",
            "Tafawa Balewa",
            "Obafemi Awolowo"
        ],
        "answer": "Tafawa Balewa"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who amalgamated Northern and Southern Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Arthur Richards",
            "John Macpherson",
            "Lord Lugard",
            "Hugh Clifford"
        ],
        "answer": "Lord Lugard"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which war lasted from 1967 to 1970 in Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Ekumeku War",
            "Nigerian Civil War",
            "Kiriji War",
            "Yoruba Civil War"
        ],
        "answer": "Nigerian Civil War"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which constitution took effect in 1999?",
        "options": [
            "1963 Constitution",
            "1979 Constitution",
            "1999 Constitution",
            "Independence Constitution"
        ],
        "answer": "1999 Constitution"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what year did Nigeria gain independence?",
        "options": [
            "1961",
            "1960",
            "1963",
            "1959"
        ],
        "answer": "1960"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was the first Nigerian Prime Minister?",
        "options": [
            "Nnamdi Azikiwe",
            "Ahmadu Bello",
            "Obafemi Awolowo",
            "Tafawa Balewa"
        ],
        "answer": "Tafawa Balewa"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who amalgamated Northern and Southern Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Arthur Richards",
            "John Macpherson",
            "Lord Lugard",
            "Hugh Clifford"
        ],
        "answer": "Lord Lugard"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which war lasted from 1967 to 1970 in Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Kiriji War",
            "Nigerian Civil War",
            "Yoruba Civil War",
            "Ekumeku War"
        ],
        "answer": "Nigerian Civil War"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which constitution took effect in 1999?",
        "options": [
            "1979 Constitution",
            "Independence Constitution",
            "1999 Constitution",
            "1963 Constitution"
        ],
        "answer": "1999 Constitution"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what year did Nigeria gain independence?",
        "options": [
            "1959",
            "1963",
            "1961",
            "1960"
        ],
        "answer": "1960"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was the first Nigerian Prime Minister?",
        "options": [
            "Ahmadu Bello",
            "Obafemi Awolowo",
            "Tafawa Balewa",
            "Nnamdi Azikiwe"
        ],
        "answer": "Tafawa Balewa"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who amalgamated Northern and Southern Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Lord Lugard",
            "Hugh Clifford",
            "John Macpherson",
            "Arthur Richards"
        ],
        "answer": "Lord Lugard"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which war lasted from 1967 to 1970 in Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Kiriji War",
            "Ekumeku War",
            "Nigerian Civil War",
            "Yoruba Civil War"
        ],
        "answer": "Nigerian Civil War"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which constitution took effect in 1999?",
        "options": [
            "Independence Constitution",
            "1999 Constitution",
            "1963 Constitution",
            "1979 Constitution"
        ],
        "answer": "1999 Constitution"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what year did Nigeria gain independence?",
        "options": [
            "1963",
            "1961",
            "1959",
            "1960"
        ],
        "answer": "1960"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was the first Nigerian Prime Minister?",
        "options": [
            "Tafawa Balewa",
            "Ahmadu Bello",
            "Nnamdi Azikiwe",
            "Obafemi Awolowo"
        ],
        "answer": "Tafawa Balewa"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who amalgamated Northern and Southern Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Arthur Richards",
            "Lord Lugard",
            "Hugh Clifford",
            "John Macpherson"
        ],
        "answer": "Lord Lugard"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which war lasted from 1967 to 1970 in Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Ekumeku War",
            "Kiriji War",
            "Yoruba Civil War",
            "Nigerian Civil War"
        ],
        "answer": "Nigerian Civil War"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which constitution took effect in 1999?",
        "options": [
            "1963 Constitution",
            "1999 Constitution",
            "1979 Constitution",
            "Independence Constitution"
        ],
        "answer": "1999 Constitution"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what year did Nigeria gain independence?",
        "options": [
            "1961",
            "1960",
            "1963",
            "1959"
        ],
        "answer": "1960"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was the first Nigerian Prime Minister?",
        "options": [
            "Obafemi Awolowo",
            "Nnamdi Azikiwe",
            "Tafawa Balewa",
            "Ahmadu Bello"
        ],
        "answer": "Tafawa Balewa"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who amalgamated Northern and Southern Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Arthur Richards",
            "John Macpherson",
            "Hugh Clifford",
            "Lord Lugard"
        ],
        "answer": "Lord Lugard"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which war lasted from 1967 to 1970 in Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Ekumeku War",
            "Kiriji War",
            "Yoruba Civil War",
            "Nigerian Civil War"
        ],
        "answer": "Nigerian Civil War"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which constitution took effect in 1999?",
        "options": [
            "1999 Constitution",
            "1979 Constitution",
            "1963 Constitution",
            "Independence Constitution"
        ],
        "answer": "1999 Constitution"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what year did Nigeria gain independence?",
        "options": [
            "1959",
            "1963",
            "1961",
            "1960"
        ],
        "answer": "1960"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was the first Nigerian Prime Minister?",
        "options": [
            "Tafawa Balewa",
            "Ahmadu Bello",
            "Nnamdi Azikiwe",
            "Obafemi Awolowo"
        ],
        "answer": "Tafawa Balewa"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who amalgamated Northern and Southern Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Arthur Richards",
            "John Macpherson",
            "Hugh Clifford",
            "Lord Lugard"
        ],
        "answer": "Lord Lugard"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which war lasted from 1967 to 1970 in Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Ekumeku War",
            "Kiriji War",
            "Yoruba Civil War",
            "Nigerian Civil War"
        ],
        "answer": "Nigerian Civil War"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which constitution took effect in 1999?",
        "options": [
            "1999 Constitution",
            "1963 Constitution",
            "1979 Constitution",
            "Independence Constitution"
        ],
        "answer": "1999 Constitution"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what year did Nigeria gain independence?",
        "options": [
            "1961",
            "1960",
            "1963",
            "1959"
        ],
        "answer": "1960"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was the first Nigerian Prime Minister?",
        "options": [
            "Tafawa Balewa",
            "Ahmadu Bello",
            "Obafemi Awolowo",
            "Nnamdi Azikiwe"
        ],
        "answer": "Tafawa Balewa"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who amalgamated Northern and Southern Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Lord Lugard",
            "Arthur Richards",
            "John Macpherson",
            "Hugh Clifford"
        ],
        "answer": "Lord Lugard"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which war lasted from 1967 to 1970 in Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Nigerian Civil War",
            "Kiriji War",
            "Ekumeku War",
            "Yoruba Civil War"
        ],
        "answer": "Nigerian Civil War"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which constitution took effect in 1999?",
        "options": [
            "1999 Constitution",
            "1963 Constitution",
            "1979 Constitution",
            "Independence Constitution"
        ],
        "answer": "1999 Constitution"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what year did Nigeria gain independence?",
        "options": [
            "1963",
            "1959",
            "1961",
            "1960"
        ],
        "answer": "1960"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was the first Nigerian Prime Minister?",
        "options": [
            "Tafawa Balewa",
            "Nnamdi Azikiwe",
            "Obafemi Awolowo",
            "Ahmadu Bello"
        ],
        "answer": "Tafawa Balewa"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who amalgamated Northern and Southern Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Arthur Richards",
            "Lord Lugard",
            "Hugh Clifford",
            "John Macpherson"
        ],
        "answer": "Lord Lugard"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which war lasted from 1967 to 1970 in Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Yoruba Civil War",
            "Kiriji War",
            "Nigerian Civil War",
            "Ekumeku War"
        ],
        "answer": "Nigerian Civil War"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which constitution took effect in 1999?",
        "options": [
            "1963 Constitution",
            "1979 Constitution",
            "1999 Constitution",
            "Independence Constitution"
        ],
        "answer": "1999 Constitution"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what year did Nigeria gain independence?",
        "options": [
            "1961",
            "1959",
            "1963",
            "1960"
        ],
        "answer": "1960"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was the first Nigerian Prime Minister?",
        "options": [
            "Nnamdi Azikiwe",
            "Obafemi Awolowo",
            "Ahmadu Bello",
            "Tafawa Balewa"
        ],
        "answer": "Tafawa Balewa"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who amalgamated Northern and Southern Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Hugh Clifford",
            "Lord Lugard",
            "John Macpherson",
            "Arthur Richards"
        ],
        "answer": "Lord Lugard"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which war lasted from 1967 to 1970 in Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Yoruba Civil War",
            "Nigerian Civil War",
            "Kiriji War",
            "Ekumeku War"
        ],
        "answer": "Nigerian Civil War"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which constitution took effect in 1999?",
        "options": [
            "1963 Constitution",
            "1979 Constitution",
            "1999 Constitution",
            "Independence Constitution"
        ],
        "answer": "1999 Constitution"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what year did Nigeria gain independence?",
        "options": [
            "1963",
            "1959",
            "1961",
            "1960"
        ],
        "answer": "1960"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was the first Nigerian Prime Minister?",
        "options": [
            "Tafawa Balewa",
            "Obafemi Awolowo",
            "Ahmadu Bello",
            "Nnamdi Azikiwe"
        ],
        "answer": "Tafawa Balewa"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who amalgamated Northern and Southern Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Hugh Clifford",
            "Arthur Richards",
            "John Macpherson",
            "Lord Lugard"
        ],
        "answer": "Lord Lugard"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which war lasted from 1967 to 1970 in Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Ekumeku War",
            "Kiriji War",
            "Yoruba Civil War",
            "Nigerian Civil War"
        ],
        "answer": "Nigerian Civil War"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which constitution took effect in 1999?",
        "options": [
            "1999 Constitution",
            "1963 Constitution",
            "Independence Constitution",
            "1979 Constitution"
        ],
        "answer": "1999 Constitution"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what year did Nigeria gain independence?",
        "options": [
            "1960",
            "1959",
            "1963",
            "1961"
        ],
        "answer": "1960"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was the first Nigerian Prime Minister?",
        "options": [
            "Nnamdi Azikiwe",
            "Tafawa Balewa",
            "Obafemi Awolowo",
            "Ahmadu Bello"
        ],
        "answer": "Tafawa Balewa"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who amalgamated Northern and Southern Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Arthur Richards",
            "Hugh Clifford",
            "John Macpherson",
            "Lord Lugard"
        ],
        "answer": "Lord Lugard"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which war lasted from 1967 to 1970 in Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Ekumeku War",
            "Yoruba Civil War",
            "Kiriji War",
            "Nigerian Civil War"
        ],
        "answer": "Nigerian Civil War"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which constitution took effect in 1999?",
        "options": [
            "Independence Constitution",
            "1999 Constitution",
            "1963 Constitution",
            "1979 Constitution"
        ],
        "answer": "1999 Constitution"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what year did Nigeria gain independence?",
        "options": [
            "1959",
            "1960",
            "1961",
            "1963"
        ],
        "answer": "1960"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was the first Nigerian Prime Minister?",
        "options": [
            "Ahmadu Bello",
            "Obafemi Awolowo",
            "Nnamdi Azikiwe",
            "Tafawa Balewa"
        ],
        "answer": "Tafawa Balewa"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who amalgamated Northern and Southern Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Hugh Clifford",
            "Lord Lugard",
            "John Macpherson",
            "Arthur Richards"
        ],
        "answer": "Lord Lugard"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which war lasted from 1967 to 1970 in Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Ekumeku War",
            "Kiriji War",
            "Nigerian Civil War",
            "Yoruba Civil War"
        ],
        "answer": "Nigerian Civil War"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which constitution took effect in 1999?",
        "options": [
            "Independence Constitution",
            "1999 Constitution",
            "1963 Constitution",
            "1979 Constitution"
        ],
        "answer": "1999 Constitution"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what year did Nigeria gain independence?",
        "options": [
            "1963",
            "1959",
            "1960",
            "1961"
        ],
        "answer": "1960"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was the first Nigerian Prime Minister?",
        "options": [
            "Nnamdi Azikiwe",
            "Obafemi Awolowo",
            "Tafawa Balewa",
            "Ahmadu Bello"
        ],
        "answer": "Tafawa Balewa"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who amalgamated Northern and Southern Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "John Macpherson",
            "Arthur Richards",
            "Hugh Clifford",
            "Lord Lugard"
        ],
        "answer": "Lord Lugard"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which war lasted from 1967 to 1970 in Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Nigerian Civil War",
            "Yoruba Civil War",
            "Kiriji War",
            "Ekumeku War"
        ],
        "answer": "Nigerian Civil War"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which constitution took effect in 1999?",
        "options": [
            "1999 Constitution",
            "1979 Constitution",
            "1963 Constitution",
            "Independence Constitution"
        ],
        "answer": "1999 Constitution"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what year did Nigeria gain independence?",
        "options": [
            "1960",
            "1959",
            "1961",
            "1963"
        ],
        "answer": "1960"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was the first Nigerian Prime Minister?",
        "options": [
            "Ahmadu Bello",
            "Tafawa Balewa",
            "Obafemi Awolowo",
            "Nnamdi Azikiwe"
        ],
        "answer": "Tafawa Balewa"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who amalgamated Northern and Southern Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Lord Lugard",
            "Hugh Clifford",
            "Arthur Richards",
            "John Macpherson"
        ],
        "answer": "Lord Lugard"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which war lasted from 1967 to 1970 in Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Kiriji War",
            "Nigerian Civil War",
            "Ekumeku War",
            "Yoruba Civil War"
        ],
        "answer": "Nigerian Civil War"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which constitution took effect in 1999?",
        "options": [
            "1963 Constitution",
            "1979 Constitution",
            "1999 Constitution",
            "Independence Constitution"
        ],
        "answer": "1999 Constitution"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what year did Nigeria gain independence?",
        "options": [
            "1963",
            "1959",
            "1960",
            "1961"
        ],
        "answer": "1960"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was the first Nigerian Prime Minister?",
        "options": [
            "Obafemi Awolowo",
            "Nnamdi Azikiwe",
            "Tafawa Balewa",
            "Ahmadu Bello"
        ],
        "answer": "Tafawa Balewa"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who amalgamated Northern and Southern Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Hugh Clifford",
            "Arthur Richards",
            "Lord Lugard",
            "John Macpherson"
        ],
        "answer": "Lord Lugard"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which war lasted from 1967 to 1970 in Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Ekumeku War",
            "Yoruba Civil War",
            "Kiriji War",
            "Nigerian Civil War"
        ],
        "answer": "Nigerian Civil War"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which constitution took effect in 1999?",
        "options": [
            "1979 Constitution",
            "1999 Constitution",
            "Independence Constitution",
            "1963 Constitution"
        ],
        "answer": "1999 Constitution"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what year did Nigeria gain independence?",
        "options": [
            "1963",
            "1959",
            "1960",
            "1961"
        ],
        "answer": "1960"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was the first Nigerian Prime Minister?",
        "options": [
            "Tafawa Balewa",
            "Ahmadu Bello",
            "Obafemi Awolowo",
            "Nnamdi Azikiwe"
        ],
        "answer": "Tafawa Balewa"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who amalgamated Northern and Southern Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "John Macpherson",
            "Lord Lugard",
            "Hugh Clifford",
            "Arthur Richards"
        ],
        "answer": "Lord Lugard"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which war lasted from 1967 to 1970 in Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Ekumeku War",
            "Nigerian Civil War",
            "Kiriji War",
            "Yoruba Civil War"
        ],
        "answer": "Nigerian Civil War"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which constitution took effect in 1999?",
        "options": [
            "1979 Constitution",
            "1999 Constitution",
            "Independence Constitution",
            "1963 Constitution"
        ],
        "answer": "1999 Constitution"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what year did Nigeria gain independence?",
        "options": [
            "1960",
            "1959",
            "1961",
            "1963"
        ],
        "answer": "1960"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was the first Nigerian Prime Minister?",
        "options": [
            "Ahmadu Bello",
            "Tafawa Balewa",
            "Obafemi Awolowo",
            "Nnamdi Azikiwe"
        ],
        "answer": "Tafawa Balewa"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who amalgamated Northern and Southern Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Arthur Richards",
            "Hugh Clifford",
            "John Macpherson",
            "Lord Lugard"
        ],
        "answer": "Lord Lugard"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which war lasted from 1967 to 1970 in Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Kiriji War",
            "Ekumeku War",
            "Yoruba Civil War",
            "Nigerian Civil War"
        ],
        "answer": "Nigerian Civil War"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which constitution took effect in 1999?",
        "options": [
            "1963 Constitution",
            "1979 Constitution",
            "Independence Constitution",
            "1999 Constitution"
        ],
        "answer": "1999 Constitution"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what year did Nigeria gain independence?",
        "options": [
            "1960",
            "1961",
            "1963",
            "1959"
        ],
        "answer": "1960"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was the first Nigerian Prime Minister?",
        "options": [
            "Tafawa Balewa",
            "Ahmadu Bello",
            "Nnamdi Azikiwe",
            "Obafemi Awolowo"
        ],
        "answer": "Tafawa Balewa"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who amalgamated Northern and Southern Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Lord Lugard",
            "John Macpherson",
            "Arthur Richards",
            "Hugh Clifford"
        ],
        "answer": "Lord Lugard"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which war lasted from 1967 to 1970 in Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Yoruba Civil War",
            "Ekumeku War",
            "Kiriji War",
            "Nigerian Civil War"
        ],
        "answer": "Nigerian Civil War"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which constitution took effect in 1999?",
        "options": [
            "1999 Constitution",
            "1979 Constitution",
            "1963 Constitution",
            "Independence Constitution"
        ],
        "answer": "1999 Constitution"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what year did Nigeria gain independence?",
        "options": [
            "1961",
            "1963",
            "1960",
            "1959"
        ],
        "answer": "1960"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was the first Nigerian Prime Minister?",
        "options": [
            "Tafawa Balewa",
            "Obafemi Awolowo",
            "Ahmadu Bello",
            "Nnamdi Azikiwe"
        ],
        "answer": "Tafawa Balewa"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who amalgamated Northern and Southern Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "John Macpherson",
            "Hugh Clifford",
            "Arthur Richards",
            "Lord Lugard"
        ],
        "answer": "Lord Lugard"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which war lasted from 1967 to 1970 in Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Ekumeku War",
            "Yoruba Civil War",
            "Nigerian Civil War",
            "Kiriji War"
        ],
        "answer": "Nigerian Civil War"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which constitution took effect in 1999?",
        "options": [
            "1963 Constitution",
            "1999 Constitution",
            "1979 Constitution",
            "Independence Constitution"
        ],
        "answer": "1999 Constitution"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what year did Nigeria gain independence?",
        "options": [
            "1963",
            "1959",
            "1961",
            "1960"
        ],
        "answer": "1960"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was the first Nigerian Prime Minister?",
        "options": [
            "Ahmadu Bello",
            "Nnamdi Azikiwe",
            "Obafemi Awolowo",
            "Tafawa Balewa"
        ],
        "answer": "Tafawa Balewa"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who amalgamated Northern and Southern Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Hugh Clifford",
            "Lord Lugard",
            "Arthur Richards",
            "John Macpherson"
        ],
        "answer": "Lord Lugard"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which war lasted from 1967 to 1970 in Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Yoruba Civil War",
            "Kiriji War",
            "Nigerian Civil War",
            "Ekumeku War"
        ],
        "answer": "Nigerian Civil War"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which constitution took effect in 1999?",
        "options": [
            "1963 Constitution",
            "1979 Constitution",
            "Independence Constitution",
            "1999 Constitution"
        ],
        "answer": "1999 Constitution"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what year did Nigeria gain independence?",
        "options": [
            "1963",
            "1960",
            "1959",
            "1961"
        ],
        "answer": "1960"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was the first Nigerian Prime Minister?",
        "options": [
            "Ahmadu Bello",
            "Tafawa Balewa",
            "Obafemi Awolowo",
            "Nnamdi Azikiwe"
        ],
        "answer": "Tafawa Balewa"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who amalgamated Northern and Southern Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Arthur Richards",
            "Hugh Clifford",
            "John Macpherson",
            "Lord Lugard"
        ],
        "answer": "Lord Lugard"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which war lasted from 1967 to 1970 in Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Kiriji War",
            "Nigerian Civil War",
            "Ekumeku War",
            "Yoruba Civil War"
        ],
        "answer": "Nigerian Civil War"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which constitution took effect in 1999?",
        "options": [
            "1979 Constitution",
            "1999 Constitution",
            "Independence Constitution",
            "1963 Constitution"
        ],
        "answer": "1999 Constitution"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what year did Nigeria gain independence?",
        "options": [
            "1960",
            "1961",
            "1959",
            "1963"
        ],
        "answer": "1960"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was the first Nigerian Prime Minister?",
        "options": [
            "Obafemi Awolowo",
            "Tafawa Balewa",
            "Nnamdi Azikiwe",
            "Ahmadu Bello"
        ],
        "answer": "Tafawa Balewa"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who amalgamated Northern and Southern Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Arthur Richards",
            "Hugh Clifford",
            "John Macpherson",
            "Lord Lugard"
        ],
        "answer": "Lord Lugard"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which war lasted from 1967 to 1970 in Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Nigerian Civil War",
            "Ekumeku War",
            "Kiriji War",
            "Yoruba Civil War"
        ],
        "answer": "Nigerian Civil War"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which constitution took effect in 1999?",
        "options": [
            "Independence Constitution",
            "1999 Constitution",
            "1979 Constitution",
            "1963 Constitution"
        ],
        "answer": "1999 Constitution"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what year did Nigeria gain independence?",
        "options": [
            "1961",
            "1963",
            "1960",
            "1959"
        ],
        "answer": "1960"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was the first Nigerian Prime Minister?",
        "options": [
            "Nnamdi Azikiwe",
            "Tafawa Balewa",
            "Ahmadu Bello",
            "Obafemi Awolowo"
        ],
        "answer": "Tafawa Balewa"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who amalgamated Northern and Southern Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Hugh Clifford",
            "Lord Lugard",
            "Arthur Richards",
            "John Macpherson"
        ],
        "answer": "Lord Lugard"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which war lasted from 1967 to 1970 in Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Kiriji War",
            "Nigerian Civil War",
            "Ekumeku War",
            "Yoruba Civil War"
        ],
        "answer": "Nigerian Civil War"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which constitution took effect in 1999?",
        "options": [
            "Independence Constitution",
            "1999 Constitution",
            "1963 Constitution",
            "1979 Constitution"
        ],
        "answer": "1999 Constitution"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what year did Nigeria gain independence?",
        "options": [
            "1959",
            "1963",
            "1961",
            "1960"
        ],
        "answer": "1960"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was the first Nigerian Prime Minister?",
        "options": [
            "Ahmadu Bello",
            "Nnamdi Azikiwe",
            "Obafemi Awolowo",
            "Tafawa Balewa"
        ],
        "answer": "Tafawa Balewa"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who amalgamated Northern and Southern Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Arthur Richards",
            "Lord Lugard",
            "John Macpherson",
            "Hugh Clifford"
        ],
        "answer": "Lord Lugard"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which war lasted from 1967 to 1970 in Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Ekumeku War",
            "Yoruba Civil War",
            "Kiriji War",
            "Nigerian Civil War"
        ],
        "answer": "Nigerian Civil War"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which constitution took effect in 1999?",
        "options": [
            "1999 Constitution",
            "Independence Constitution",
            "1979 Constitution",
            "1963 Constitution"
        ],
        "answer": "1999 Constitution"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what year did Nigeria gain independence?",
        "options": [
            "1961",
            "1959",
            "1960",
            "1963"
        ],
        "answer": "1960"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was the first Nigerian Prime Minister?",
        "options": [
            "Ahmadu Bello",
            "Tafawa Balewa",
            "Obafemi Awolowo",
            "Nnamdi Azikiwe"
        ],
        "answer": "Tafawa Balewa"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who amalgamated Northern and Southern Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "John Macpherson",
            "Arthur Richards",
            "Hugh Clifford",
            "Lord Lugard"
        ],
        "answer": "Lord Lugard"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which war lasted from 1967 to 1970 in Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Yoruba Civil War",
            "Nigerian Civil War",
            "Ekumeku War",
            "Kiriji War"
        ],
        "answer": "Nigerian Civil War"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which constitution took effect in 1999?",
        "options": [
            "1963 Constitution",
            "Independence Constitution",
            "1979 Constitution",
            "1999 Constitution"
        ],
        "answer": "1999 Constitution"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what year did Nigeria gain independence?",
        "options": [
            "1960",
            "1961",
            "1963",
            "1959"
        ],
        "answer": "1960"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was the first Nigerian Prime Minister?",
        "options": [
            "Nnamdi Azikiwe",
            "Obafemi Awolowo",
            "Tafawa Balewa",
            "Ahmadu Bello"
        ],
        "answer": "Tafawa Balewa"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who amalgamated Northern and Southern Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "John Macpherson",
            "Arthur Richards",
            "Hugh Clifford",
            "Lord Lugard"
        ],
        "answer": "Lord Lugard"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which war lasted from 1967 to 1970 in Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Nigerian Civil War",
            "Kiriji War",
            "Yoruba Civil War",
            "Ekumeku War"
        ],
        "answer": "Nigerian Civil War"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which constitution took effect in 1999?",
        "options": [
            "Independence Constitution",
            "1999 Constitution",
            "1963 Constitution",
            "1979 Constitution"
        ],
        "answer": "1999 Constitution"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what year did Nigeria gain independence?",
        "options": [
            "1961",
            "1963",
            "1960",
            "1959"
        ],
        "answer": "1960"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was the first Nigerian Prime Minister?",
        "options": [
            "Tafawa Balewa",
            "Obafemi Awolowo",
            "Ahmadu Bello",
            "Nnamdi Azikiwe"
        ],
        "answer": "Tafawa Balewa"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who amalgamated Northern and Southern Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Lord Lugard",
            "Hugh Clifford",
            "Arthur Richards",
            "John Macpherson"
        ],
        "answer": "Lord Lugard"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which war lasted from 1967 to 1970 in Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Nigerian Civil War",
            "Ekumeku War",
            "Kiriji War",
            "Yoruba Civil War"
        ],
        "answer": "Nigerian Civil War"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which constitution took effect in 1999?",
        "options": [
            "1963 Constitution",
            "Independence Constitution",
            "1979 Constitution",
            "1999 Constitution"
        ],
        "answer": "1999 Constitution"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what year did Nigeria gain independence?",
        "options": [
            "1961",
            "1960",
            "1963",
            "1959"
        ],
        "answer": "1960"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was the first Nigerian Prime Minister?",
        "options": [
            "Tafawa Balewa",
            "Nnamdi Azikiwe",
            "Ahmadu Bello",
            "Obafemi Awolowo"
        ],
        "answer": "Tafawa Balewa"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who amalgamated Northern and Southern Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Hugh Clifford",
            "Arthur Richards",
            "Lord Lugard",
            "John Macpherson"
        ],
        "answer": "Lord Lugard"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which war lasted from 1967 to 1970 in Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Kiriji War",
            "Ekumeku War",
            "Yoruba Civil War",
            "Nigerian Civil War"
        ],
        "answer": "Nigerian Civil War"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which constitution took effect in 1999?",
        "options": [
            "1979 Constitution",
            "1999 Constitution",
            "Independence Constitution",
            "1963 Constitution"
        ],
        "answer": "1999 Constitution"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what year did Nigeria gain independence?",
        "options": [
            "1963",
            "1961",
            "1959",
            "1960"
        ],
        "answer": "1960"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was the first Nigerian Prime Minister?",
        "options": [
            "Obafemi Awolowo",
            "Tafawa Balewa",
            "Ahmadu Bello",
            "Nnamdi Azikiwe"
        ],
        "answer": "Tafawa Balewa"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who amalgamated Northern and Southern Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Hugh Clifford",
            "Arthur Richards",
            "Lord Lugard",
            "John Macpherson"
        ],
        "answer": "Lord Lugard"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which war lasted from 1967 to 1970 in Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Kiriji War",
            "Nigerian Civil War",
            "Ekumeku War",
            "Yoruba Civil War"
        ],
        "answer": "Nigerian Civil War"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which constitution took effect in 1999?",
        "options": [
            "1999 Constitution",
            "Independence Constitution",
            "1963 Constitution",
            "1979 Constitution"
        ],
        "answer": "1999 Constitution"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what year did Nigeria gain independence?",
        "options": [
            "1963",
            "1961",
            "1959",
            "1960"
        ],
        "answer": "1960"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was the first Nigerian Prime Minister?",
        "options": [
            "Obafemi Awolowo",
            "Nnamdi Azikiwe",
            "Ahmadu Bello",
            "Tafawa Balewa"
        ],
        "answer": "Tafawa Balewa"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who amalgamated Northern and Southern Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Lord Lugard",
            "Hugh Clifford",
            "Arthur Richards",
            "John Macpherson"
        ],
        "answer": "Lord Lugard"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which war lasted from 1967 to 1970 in Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Yoruba Civil War",
            "Kiriji War",
            "Ekumeku War",
            "Nigerian Civil War"
        ],
        "answer": "Nigerian Civil War"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which constitution took effect in 1999?",
        "options": [
            "1979 Constitution",
            "1963 Constitution",
            "1999 Constitution",
            "Independence Constitution"
        ],
        "answer": "1999 Constitution"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what year did Nigeria gain independence?",
        "options": [
            "1963",
            "1959",
            "1961",
            "1960"
        ],
        "answer": "1960"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was the first Nigerian Prime Minister?",
        "options": [
            "Nnamdi Azikiwe",
            "Obafemi Awolowo",
            "Ahmadu Bello",
            "Tafawa Balewa"
        ],
        "answer": "Tafawa Balewa"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who amalgamated Northern and Southern Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Hugh Clifford",
            "Arthur Richards",
            "Lord Lugard",
            "John Macpherson"
        ],
        "answer": "Lord Lugard"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which war lasted from 1967 to 1970 in Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Nigerian Civil War",
            "Kiriji War",
            "Yoruba Civil War",
            "Ekumeku War"
        ],
        "answer": "Nigerian Civil War"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which constitution took effect in 1999?",
        "options": [
            "1963 Constitution",
            "1999 Constitution",
            "Independence Constitution",
            "1979 Constitution"
        ],
        "answer": "1999 Constitution"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what year did Nigeria gain independence?",
        "options": [
            "1960",
            "1959",
            "1963",
            "1961"
        ],
        "answer": "1960"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was the first Nigerian Prime Minister?",
        "options": [
            "Nnamdi Azikiwe",
            "Ahmadu Bello",
            "Tafawa Balewa",
            "Obafemi Awolowo"
        ],
        "answer": "Tafawa Balewa"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who amalgamated Northern and Southern Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Arthur Richards",
            "Lord Lugard",
            "John Macpherson",
            "Hugh Clifford"
        ],
        "answer": "Lord Lugard"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which war lasted from 1967 to 1970 in Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Nigerian Civil War",
            "Yoruba Civil War",
            "Ekumeku War",
            "Kiriji War"
        ],
        "answer": "Nigerian Civil War"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which constitution took effect in 1999?",
        "options": [
            "Independence Constitution",
            "1999 Constitution",
            "1963 Constitution",
            "1979 Constitution"
        ],
        "answer": "1999 Constitution"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what year did Nigeria gain independence?",
        "options": [
            "1961",
            "1959",
            "1963",
            "1960"
        ],
        "answer": "1960"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was the first Nigerian Prime Minister?",
        "options": [
            "Nnamdi Azikiwe",
            "Obafemi Awolowo",
            "Ahmadu Bello",
            "Tafawa Balewa"
        ],
        "answer": "Tafawa Balewa"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who amalgamated Northern and Southern Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Arthur Richards",
            "Hugh Clifford",
            "Lord Lugard",
            "John Macpherson"
        ],
        "answer": "Lord Lugard"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which war lasted from 1967 to 1970 in Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Yoruba Civil War",
            "Ekumeku War",
            "Kiriji War",
            "Nigerian Civil War"
        ],
        "answer": "Nigerian Civil War"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which constitution took effect in 1999?",
        "options": [
            "Independence Constitution",
            "1963 Constitution",
            "1979 Constitution",
            "1999 Constitution"
        ],
        "answer": "1999 Constitution"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what year did Nigeria gain independence?",
        "options": [
            "1959",
            "1961",
            "1960",
            "1963"
        ],
        "answer": "1960"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was the first Nigerian Prime Minister?",
        "options": [
            "Obafemi Awolowo",
            "Ahmadu Bello",
            "Nnamdi Azikiwe",
            "Tafawa Balewa"
        ],
        "answer": "Tafawa Balewa"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who amalgamated Northern and Southern Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "John Macpherson",
            "Arthur Richards",
            "Lord Lugard",
            "Hugh Clifford"
        ],
        "answer": "Lord Lugard"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which war lasted from 1967 to 1970 in Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Kiriji War",
            "Yoruba Civil War",
            "Nigerian Civil War",
            "Ekumeku War"
        ],
        "answer": "Nigerian Civil War"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which constitution took effect in 1999?",
        "options": [
            "1999 Constitution",
            "1979 Constitution",
            "Independence Constitution",
            "1963 Constitution"
        ],
        "answer": "1999 Constitution"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what year did Nigeria gain independence?",
        "options": [
            "1959",
            "1961",
            "1963",
            "1960"
        ],
        "answer": "1960"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was the first Nigerian Prime Minister?",
        "options": [
            "Tafawa Balewa",
            "Nnamdi Azikiwe",
            "Ahmadu Bello",
            "Obafemi Awolowo"
        ],
        "answer": "Tafawa Balewa"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who amalgamated Northern and Southern Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Hugh Clifford",
            "John Macpherson",
            "Lord Lugard",
            "Arthur Richards"
        ],
        "answer": "Lord Lugard"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which war lasted from 1967 to 1970 in Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Nigerian Civil War",
            "Yoruba Civil War",
            "Ekumeku War",
            "Kiriji War"
        ],
        "answer": "Nigerian Civil War"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which constitution took effect in 1999?",
        "options": [
            "1979 Constitution",
            "Independence Constitution",
            "1963 Constitution",
            "1999 Constitution"
        ],
        "answer": "1999 Constitution"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what year did Nigeria gain independence?",
        "options": [
            "1959",
            "1960",
            "1963",
            "1961"
        ],
        "answer": "1960"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was the first Nigerian Prime Minister?",
        "options": [
            "Obafemi Awolowo",
            "Tafawa Balewa",
            "Nnamdi Azikiwe",
            "Ahmadu Bello"
        ],
        "answer": "Tafawa Balewa"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who amalgamated Northern and Southern Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Hugh Clifford",
            "Arthur Richards",
            "John Macpherson",
            "Lord Lugard"
        ],
        "answer": "Lord Lugard"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which war lasted from 1967 to 1970 in Nigeria?",
        "options": [
            "Ekumeku War",
            "Kiriji War",
            "Yoruba Civil War",
            "Nigerian Civil War"
        ],
        "answer": "Nigerian Civil War"
    }
]